Guide to the Walter Brattain family papers 1860-1990
Whitman College and Northwest Archives
- Career, 1917-1989; 2; 11 linear feet
  - Speeches and Writings, 1924-1981; 3
    - P.N. Sawyer, Kwang-Tzen Wu, S.A. Wesolowski, W.H. Brattain, and P.J. Boddy, "Electrochemical Precipitation of Blood Cells on Metal Electrodes: An Aid in the Selection of Vascular Prostheses?", 1965 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - A.M. Portis, A.F. Kip, C. Kittel, and W.H. Brattain, "Electron Spin Resonance in a Silicon Semiconductor", 1953 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - "Evidence for Surface States on Semiconductors from Change in Constant Potential on Illumination", 1947 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - "Historical Development of Concepts Basic to the Understanding of Semiconductors", 1968 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - W.H. Brattain and P.J. Boddy, "Interaction of Iodide Ion with Germanium Electrodes", 1965 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - J. Bardeen, W.H. Brattain, and W. Shockley, "Investigation of Oxidation of Copper by Use of Radioactive Cu Tracer", 1946 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - T.M. Buck and W.H. Brattain, "Investigations of Surface Recombination Velocities on Ge by the Photoelectromagnetic Methods", 1955 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - "Irreversible Electrochemical Precipitation of Mammalian Platelets and Intravascular Thrombosis", 1964 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - "Introduction to the Chemistry and Physics of Surfaces", undated (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - P.N. Sawyer, K.T. Wu, S.A. Wesolowski, W.H. Brattain, and P.J. Boddy, "Long-Term Potency of Solid-Wall Vascular Prosthesis", 1965 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Memorandum: "A Vacuum System for Vaporization of Metal Contacts Onto Copper-Oxide Varistors" (includes photographs), 1937 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - Old Abstracts, 1930-1937 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - College Association for Public Events and Services (California), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - D.R. Kalkwarf, D.L. Frasco, and W.H. Brattain, "Current Rectification and Action Potentials Across Thin Lipid Membranes" and "Ion-Diffusion Potentials and Electrification Rectification Across Lipid Membranes Activated by Excitation-Induced Material", 1972 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - W.H. Brattain and P.J. Boddy, "Surface States at a Germanium-Electrolyte Interface", 1962 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - "Rectification Series" abstract, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - P.J. Boddy and W.H. Brattain, "Residual Surface Recombination of Germanium Anodes", 1965 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - "Semiconductor Surface Phenomena", 1950 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - "Photo Cells at the Surface of a Semiconductor" (including photographs), 1944 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - W.H. Brattain and C.G.B. Garrett, "Surface Properties of Germanium and Silicon", 1954 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - "Surface Properties of Semiconductors," lecture to the Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - J.A. Becker and W.H. Brattain, "Thermionic Work Function of Slope and Intercept of Richardson Plots", 1934 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Varistors, including "The Copper Oxide Varistor" by Walter Brattain, undated (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - D.R. Kalkwarf, D.L. Frasco and W.H. Brattain, "Current Rectification and Action Potentials Across Thin Lipid Membranes", undated (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - J.A. Becker and W.H. Brattain, "Useful Equations in the Design of Thermistors", 1944 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - "Development of Concepts in Semiconductor Research," Richtmyer Lecture, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - "Dependence of Small Signal Parameters of n-p-n Transistors on Width of Collector Space Charge Layer", 1953 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - "John Dewey" Essay, undated (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - "Paper for Cross Roads", circa 1925 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Personal, undated (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - Bell Telephone System Monographs, volume 1, 1947-1950 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Bell Telephone System Monographs, volume 2, 1950-1952 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Bell Telephone System Monographs, volume 3, 1951-1953 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Bell Telephone System Monographs, volume 4, 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Bell Telephone System Monographs, volume 5, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Bell Telephone System Semiconductor Monographs, volume 1, 1946-1951 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Bell Telephone System Semiconductor Monographs, volume 2, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Bell Telephone System Semiconductor Monographs, volume 3, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Reprints of Articles by Walter Brattain, 1949-1962 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Conferences, 1948-1981; 4
    This sub-series includes itineraries, pamphlets, and correspondence related to conferences Walter Brattain attended around the world.
    - Itinerary for Stockholm Trip, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Amsterdam Conference, 1953-1954 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Basel, Switzerland, International Union of Pure and Applied Physics, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Boston, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Brussels and Europe, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Brussels International Physics Conference (Photos), 1958 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Brussels Telecommunications Exposition, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - California Institute of Technology Albuquerque Trip, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - California Institute of Technology's 75th Anniversary, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Cambridge – 10th International Conference on the Physics of Semiconductors, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - China, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - China Trip Directory, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Columbia Basin College, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Conference on Physics of Semiconductor Surface, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Devices Research Conference, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Europe, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Europe, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Europe, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Europe Reservations and Expenses, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Exeter Attendees, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Gordon Conference, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Gustavius Adolphus, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - International Conference on the Physics and Chemistry of Solid Surface Guest List, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Photo Identification for the International Conference on Semi-Conductors, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Japan, 1, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Japan, 2, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Japan, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Korea, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Kwajalein, Marshall Islands: Bell Laboratories Conference, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Lindau Attendees, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Lindau - Exeter, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Lindau, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Lindau, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Lindau Attendee List, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Lindau – Meeting of Nobel Prize Winners, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - London Institute of Electrical Engineers, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - London – 50th Meeting of the Naval Research Advisory Committee, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - London, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Moscow, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Northwest Regional Energy Conference, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Paris, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Physics of Semiconductors Conference, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Pittsburg Convocation of Nobel Laureates, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Pittsburg Convocation of Nobel Laureates Photographs, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Portland, Oregon, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), May 27, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Portland, Oregon, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Prague, (Czechoslovakia) Czech Republic, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Providence Conference on the Physics and Chemistry of Solid Surfaces, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Reading – First Trip, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Rochester Semiconductor Conference, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Russian Visits, 1956-1963 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Stockholm, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Solid State Seminar, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Stuttgart, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Taipei, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Tehran, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Transistor Conferences, 1948, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Travel, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Trip Expense Accounts, 1948-1960 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Versailles Conference, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Visiting Scientists Program in Physics, 1959-1961 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Experiments and Data, 1929-1977; 5
    - Α (Alpha) Particles, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Ana Data, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Ana Data, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Ana Data, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Apparatus, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Auxiliary Data and Calculation, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - CaCl, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Circuit Problems, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Data Notes, 1, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Data Notes, 2, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Data Notes, 3, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Data, 4, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Data and Averages, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Data on EIM-activated membranes, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Data on EIM-activated membranes, July, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Equations and Proofs, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Figures, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Figures and Tables, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Delta G versus Y, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - J.A. Hornbeck and P.W Foy, "Ohmic Contacts as a Source of Reverse Saturation Currents in p-n Junctions," paper abstract, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Index Refraction, undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Inductance, 1, undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Inductance, 2, undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - KCl data, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - KFl/KBr/(CH3)4HCl/NH4Cl, undated (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - K2SO4, undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Lipids, 1, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Lipids, 2, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Microscopic Examination of the Copper-Cuprous Oxide Interface of Copper-Oxide Varistors, with Plates, undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous Experiments, undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - NaCl, undated (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Nerves, undated (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Optical Constants of Ge Papers, undated (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Optical Thickness, undated (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Optical Thickness, undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Patent Application number 11,165 (Continuation of Transistor), undated (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Patent Application Infra-Red Detectors and Recorder, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Patent Application, November 14, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Patents 1 to 6, undated (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Patents 1-7, 3-9 (Brattain- Bardeen), undated (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Patents 4-11, 5-12, 6-13 (Brattain – Bardeen), undated (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - Patent – Three Electrode Circuit (John Bardeen and Walter Brattain), 1950 (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - Insulators, undated (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - Progress Reports, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Notebook Inventories, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - "The Results of a Study of the Current Voltage Characteristics of Cu2O Rectifier Unit", 1935 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Rhodium Plating, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Germanium Etches, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Salt Bias, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Silicon, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Silicon n and k Data, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Silicon Rectifier, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Silicon Reports, etc., undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Theory of Semiconductors and Rectification, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Transmissions Through Thin Films, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - "A Vacuum System for Vaporization of Metal Contacts onto Contact Oxide Varistors", 1937 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Vapor Pressure, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Lab Notebooks, undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Membrane Data Charts, 1977 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Honors, Awards, and Recognitions, 1917-1989; 6
    - Awards and Certificates, 1953-1966 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Defense Science Board, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Nobel Science Hall Dedication, Gustavus Adolphus College, Minnesota, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Washington Centennial Hall of Honor Catalog, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - University of Oregon Alumnus of the Year Award, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - University of Minnesota Honorary Doctor of Science Degree, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Nobel Prize Announcement, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Nobel Prize Ceremony Invitation, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Nobel Transistor Demonstration Materials, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Nobel Ceremony Activities, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Nobel Trip Expenses, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Nobel Laureates Dinner at White House, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Recognitions and Articles, 1966-1981 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Retirement, Bell Labs, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence with Sweden before and after Nobel Trip, 1956 – 1957 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence List for Nobel Congratulations, undated (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Nobel Prize Congratulations and Clippings, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Nobel Prize Clippings and Anniversary Celebrations, 1956-1982 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Nobel Laureate Day Photo Album, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - American Institute of Physics, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Awards, 1925, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Brain Life Research Foundation, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Federation of American Scientists, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Franklin Institute, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Franklin Institute - Stuart Ballantine Medal, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - National Inventors Hall of Fame, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Washington State Historical Society Hall of Honor, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Historical Library and Museum of Science and Technology, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - International Conference on the Unity of the Sciences (ICUS), 1978-1981 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - ICUS & Reverend Sun Myung Moon, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Awards, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - International Union of Pure and Applied Physics (IUPAP), 1968-1973 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - International Union of Pure and Applied Physics 50th anniversary, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - International Union of Pure and Applied Physics, General Information and Report of the General assembly, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - International Union of Pure and Applied Physics, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - USA National Committee of International Union of Pure and Applied Physics, 1965-1969 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Joint Center for Graduate Study Advisory Committee, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Land Grant College Dinner, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Museum of Science and Industry – Nobel, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1965-1971 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - National Academy of Sciences – Members Directory, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - National Academy of Sciences Pamphlets, 1970-1982 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1975 – 1977 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - National Science Foundation, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Portland Rotary Club, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - John Scott Medal clippings, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Semiconductor Equipment and Materials Institute (SEMI), 1977 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Sigma Xi, 1966-1970 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Stoics 1, 1966-1977 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Stoics 2, 1962-1966 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Stoics 3, 1962-1964 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Walla Walla Chamber of Commerce Award - Clippings, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Bell Advancement, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Bell Telephone Laboratories Press Releases with Photographs, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Bell Laboratories Publications, 1948-1983 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Bell Laboratories News 1, 1968-1982 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Bell Laboratories News 2, 1962-1975 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Fortune, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Magazine Articles about Walter Brattain, 1956-1968 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Battelle Memorial Institute, 1969-1972 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Official Transcript Nobel Conference Proceedings – Shaping the Future, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Convocation of Nobel Laureates, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Nobel Announcement, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Nobel Dedication, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Nobel Laureates White House Dinner, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Nobel Photo – Prized Minds, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - "Nobel Prize for Physics", 1956 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Reproduction of Alfred Nobel's Signature, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Swedish Newspaper Clippings for Nobel Awards, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Alexander Dees De Sterio, Nobelpreistrager in Lindau, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Erich Bagge, Die Nobelpreistrager der Physik, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Alexander Dees De Sterio, Nobel fuhrte sie zusammen Begegnungun in Lindau, signed by Walter Brattain, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Scrapbook Album, Texas Instruments Dedication, Walter Brattain Honored Guest, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbooks, Retirement from Bell Labs, 3 Volumes, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 2-4)
    - Naval Research Advisory Committee certificate of membership, 1960 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Life magazine article: Nobel Winners at White House Dinner, 1962 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Diplomas, Certificates and Awards, 1917-1984 (Box 45, Folder 8)
- Reference Materials, 1860-1989; 3; 6 linear feet
  This series consists of science articles and subject files collected by Walter Brattain, reflecting his professional and personal interests. Some files also contain related correspondence.
  - Robert E. Ackerman, "Report to National Academy of Sciences: Senior Scientist Exchange Program to the U.S.S.R., undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Artificial Heart Program, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Astronomy articles, 1964-1967 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Auroral Plasma Experimental Papers, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Basic Constants, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Hanford 200 Bev accelerator, 1965-1970 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - "Bioelectric Control of Bioluminescence in the Dinoflagellate Noctiluca", 1965 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - C.G.B. Garrett, "Surface Thermodynamics", undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Benjamin Brown, Whitman College professor, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Tektronix, "A Practical Approach to Transistor and Vacuum Tube Amplifiers", 1967 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - "Conductance of the Sodium Channel in Mylinated Nerve Fibers with Modified Sodium Inactivation", 1976 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - "The Work Required to Remove an Electron from a Conducting Sphere", undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Cordiner Hall Acoustics, 1965-1972 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Copper Oxide Material, 1969-1976 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Student Dissent, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - DNA, 1961-1964 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Drell Report – Arms Control, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - "Drugs and Transport Processes", undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Earth Weighing Machine, including photograph, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Ecological Crises Readings, 1965-1970 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Ecology Copies, 1975-1976 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - "The Electrical Activity of the Nervous System", 1964 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Energy and Ecology, including notes by Brattain, 1967-1975 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Energy Per Bit, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Energy Policy, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Environment, 1969-1973 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Genetic Codes, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Germanium, 1961-1966 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Hodgkin – Huxley articles, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - "Ion Transport Across the Lipid Membranes: A Critical Discussion of Mechanism in Selected Systems", 1972 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - "Ion Transport Through Excitability-Inducing Material (EIM) Channels in Lipid Bilayer Membranes", 1972 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Karl Jansky—search for intelligent life, photographs of Bell Laboratories, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - "Schottky's Theories of Dry Solid Rectifiers", 1944 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Professor Sergey Kalashnikov, exchange visit to Walla Walla, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - "Kinetic Characteristics of the Excitability- Inducing Material Channel in Oxidized Cholesterol and Brain Lipids Bilayer Membranes", 1975 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - "Kinetics of the Opening and Closing of Individual Excitability- Inducing Material Channel in a Lipid Bilayer", 1974 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Benjamin Brown, A Little Astronomy pamphlet, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - A. H. Madjid Articles – Crystals, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - "The Logic of Measurement in Quantum Physics", undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Metallurgy, 1948, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - "Molecular Model-Potentials: Combination of Atomic Boxes", undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Mueller and Rudin—Bimolecular Lipid Membranes, 1962-1976 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - "The Nature of the Negative Resistance in Bimolecular Lipid Membranes Containing Excitability-Inducing Material", 1970 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - The Nature of Science, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - National Geographic article: "Those Inventive Americans," including section on transistor, 1970-1971 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Pacific Science Center, 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Plate Tectonics, 1961-1971 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Research in Science Education, 1978-1980 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - "Resting Potentials, Action Potentials, and Potassium Selectivity in Experimental Bimolecular Lipid Membrane", 1966, 1980-1981 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Science Articles, 1970-1973 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Benjamin Brown, "Seeing Walla Walla First", undated (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Semiconductor Bibliography, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Solid-State Physics History, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - "Stability of the Myelin Membrane", 1965 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Benjamin Brown, "The State-line Earthquake at Milton and Walla Walla", 1936 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Thermistor Bolometers, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Thermistor Reports, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Thermistor – High Speed, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Time Charts, undated (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Tungsten, 1925-1927 (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - John Bardeen Biography of Walter Brattain, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Biographical and Bibliographical Information, 1945-1981 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Biography, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Current Biography – Who's News and Why, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - New Book of Knowledge Articles (Biography & Discovery of the Transistor), 1947-1978 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Who's Who Biography, 1974-1981 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Campbell Gay - story, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Foreign Clippings, 1956-1971 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Nobel Articles (not related to Brattain), 1978, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - A Nobel Laureate and his Nobel Laureate Friends, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Personal News, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Post Nobel Articles about Brattain, 1955-1960 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Post – Nobel News, 1961-1977 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Post – Retirement Research and Opinions, 1959-1979 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Recent Visitors to the Laboratories, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Rock&Roll Regret, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Alumni Funds, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Alumni Funds, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Drive for Brown Chair of Physics, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Faculty – Governing Boards Conference, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Four Horsemen Reunion, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Retirement to Whitman - Clippings, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Small College Promotion, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Tributes to Brown, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 24)